Welcome back. Here is my solution for the softmax function.
欢迎回来下面介绍下我是如何实现 softmax 函数的
Here in the numerator,
在分子中
we know we want to take the exponential,
我们希望计算指数
so it's pretty straight forward with torch.exp.
因此 torch.exp 很好理解
So we're going to use the exponential of x,
我们将对 x 求指数
which is our input tensor.
x 是输入张量
In the denominator, we know we want to do something like,
在分母中也要计算指数
again take exponentials so torch.exp,
因此使用 torch.exp
and then take the sum across all those values.
然后对所有这些值求和
So, one thing we need to remember is that we want the sum across one single row.
要注意的一点是 我们要对一行求和
So, each of the columns in one single row for each example.
即一行中的每列 表示每个样本
So, for one example, we want to sum up those values.
对于一个样本 我们想对这些值求和
So, for here in torch.sum,
在 torch.sum 中
we're going to use dimension equals one.
将维度设为 1
So, this is basically going to take the sum across the columns.
这样就会对列求和
What this does, torch.sum here,
这里的 torch.sum
is going to actually going to give us a tensor,
将返回一个张量
that is just a vector of 64 elements.
也就是有 64 个元素的向量
So, the problem with this is that,
现在的问题是
if this is 64 by 10,
这是 64 x 10
and this is just a 64-long vector,
这是长为 64 的向量
it's going to try to divide every element in this tensor by all 64 of these values.
它将使该张量里的每个元素除以所有 64 个值
So, it's going give us a 64 by 64 tensor, and that's not what we want.
结果是 64 x 64 张量 这不是我们想要的结果
We want our output to be 64 by 10.
我们希望输出是 64 x 10
So, what you actually need to do is reshape this tensor here to have 64 rows,
因此我们需要将这个张量变形为 64 行
but only one value for each of those rows.
但是每行只有一个值
So, what that's going do,
这样的话
it's going look at for each row in this tensor,
它将查看这个张量里的每行
is going to look at the equivalent row in this tensor.
将查看这个张量里的对等行
So, since each row in this tensor only has one value,
由于这个张量里的每行只有一个值
it's going to divide this exponential by the one value in this denominator tensor.
因此它将使这个指数值除以分母张量里的一个值
This can be really tricky,
听起来有点复杂
but it's also super important to understand how broadcasting works in PyTorch,
我们首先要理解 PyTorch 中的广播概念
and how to actually fit all these tensors together with
以及如何使所有这些张量具有正确的形状
the correct shape and the correct operations to get everything out right.
并执行正确的操作
So, if we do this, it look what we have,
这么操作后
we pass our output through the softmax function,
将输出传入 softmax 函数
and then we get our probabilities,
获得概率
and we can look the shape and it is 64 by 10,
看看形状 形状为 64 x 10
and if you take the sum across each of the rows,
如果对每行求和
then it adds up to one,
会发现和为 1
like it should with a proper probability distribution.
符合正常的概率分布
So, now, we're going to look at how you use this nn module to build neural networks.
现在看看如何使用 nn 模块便捷地
So, you'll find that it's actually in a lot of ways simpler and more powerful.
构建强大的神经网络
You'll be able to build larger and larger neural networks using the same framework.
你将能够使用相同的框架构建越来越大的神经网络
The way this works in general,
大概原理如下
is that we're going to create a new class,
创建新的类
and you can call it networking,
称之为 Network
you can call it whatever you want,
当然也可以叫其他任何名称
you can call it classifier,
可以叫 Classifier
you can call it MNIST.
可以叫 MNIST
It doesn't really matter so much what you call it,
叫什么都不重要
but you need to subclass it from nn.module.
但是必须是 nn.Module 的子类
Then, in the init method, it's __init method.
然后在 __init__ 方法里
You need to call it super and run the init method of nn.module.
你需要调用 super() 并运行 nn.Module 的 init 方法
So, you need to do this because then,
这么做的原因是
PyTorch will know to register
让 PyTorch 知道 要去注册
all the different layers and
你添加到网络里的
operations that you're going to be putting into this network.
所有不同层级和操作
If you don't do this part then,
如果没有这部分代码
it won't be able to track the things that
PyTorch 将无法跟踪
you're adding to your network, and it just won't work.
你添加到网络里的内容
So, here, we can create our hidden layers using nn.Linear.
在这里使用 nn.Linear 创建隐藏层
So, what this does,
它的作用是
is it creates a operation for the linear transformation.
为线性转换创建操作
So, when we take our inputs x and then multiply it by weights and add your bias terms,
我们将输入 x 与权重相乘并加上偏差项
that's a linear transformation.
这就是线性转换
So, what this does is calling NN.Linear,
这行代码会调用 nn.Linear
it creates an object that itself has created
它将创建一个对象
parameters for the weights and parameters for the bias and then,
对象本身将创建权重参数和偏差参数
when you pass a tensor through this hidden layer,
然后将张量传入这个隐藏层（这个对象）
this object, it's going to automatically calculate the linear transformation for you.
它将自动为你计算线性转换结果
So, all you really need to do is tell it what's the size of the inputs,
你只需传入输入大小
and then what are the size of the output.
和输出大小
So, 784 by 256,
即 784 x 256
we're going to use 256 outputs for this.
我们需要 256 个输出
So, it's kind of rebuilding the network that we saw before.
是不是有点像对之前网络的重新构建
Similarly, we want another linear transformation between our hidden units and our output.
同理 我们希望在隐藏单元和输出之间进行线性转换
So, again, we have 256 hidden units,
我们有 256 个隐藏单元
and we have 10 outputs, 10 output units,
有 10 个输出单元
so we're going to create a output layer called self.output,
我们将创建一个输出层 叫做 self.output
and create this linear transformation operation.
并创建这个线性转换操作
We also want to create a sigmoid operation for the activation and then,
还需要创建 S 型激活函数
softmax for the output,
并为输出创建 softmax 函数
so we get this probability distribution.
从而获取概率分布
Now, we're going to create a forward method and so,
现在创建 forward 方法
forward is basically going to be,
forward 是指
as we pass a tensor in to the network.
向网络里传入一个张量
It's gonna go through all these operations,
该张量将经过所有这些操作
and eventually give us our output.
最终获得输出
So, here, x, the argument is going to be the input tensor and then,
这里的参数 x 将为输入张量
we're going to pass it through our hidden layer.
然后使其经过隐藏层
So, this is again, like this linear transformation that we defined up here,
这个和这里定义的线性转换一样
and it's going to go through a sigmoid activation,
它将经过 S 型激活函数
and then through our output layer or output linear transformation, we have here,
然后经过输出层 即这里的输出线性转换
and then through the sigmoid function,
然后经过 S 型函数
and then finally return the output of our softmax.
最终返回 softmax 的输出
so we can create this.
创建这个网络
Then, if we kind of look at it, so it'll print it out,
输出网络 看看结果如何
and it'll tell us the operations, and not necessarily the order,
系统将显示各项操作 但不一定按顺序展示
but at least it tells us the operations that we have defined for this network.
但至少会显示我们为这个网络定义的操作
You can also use some functional definitions for things like sigmoid and softmax,
你还可以函数形式定义 S 型函数或 softmax
and it kind of makes the class the way you write the code a little bit cleaner.
这样会使该类/代码看起来更整洁
We can get that from torch.nn.functional.
我们可以使用 torch.nn.functional 模块
Most of the time, you'll see is like import torch.nn.functional as capital F. So,
大多数情况下 你会看到 import torch.nn.functional 设为大写的 F
there's kind of that convention in PyTorch code.
这是一种 PyTorch 代码编写惯例
So, again, we define our linear transformations,
定义线性转换 self.hidden self.output
self.hidden, self.output but now in our forward method.
但是现在在 forward 方法里
So, we can call self.hidden to get like our values for hidden layer, but then,
我们可以调用 self.hidden 以获取隐藏层的值
we pass it through the sigmoid function,
然后传入 S 型函数里 即 F.sigmoid
f.sigmoid, and the same thing with the output layers.
输出层也一样
So, we have our output linear transformations of the output,
创建输出线性转换
and we pass it through this softmax operation.
传入 softmax 函数里
So, the reason we can do this because,
能这么操作的原因是
when we create these linear transformations,
当我们创建这些线性转换时
it's creating the weights and bias matrices on its own.
它们会自己创建权重和偏差矩阵
But for sigmoid and softmax,
但是对于 S 型函数和 softmax
it's just an element wise operation,
它们是元素级操作
so it doesn't have to create any extra parameters
不需要创建额外的参数或额外的矩阵
or extra matrices to do these operations,
就能执行这些操作
and so we can have these be purely functional
因此这些可以是纯函数定义
without having to create any sort of object or classes.
无需创建任何对象或类
However, they are equivalent.
但是它们是等同的
So this way to build the network is equivalent to this way up here,
这种网络构建方式和上面的效果一样
but it's a little bit more succinct when you're
但是采用这种函数格式
doing it with these kind of functional pattern.
使代码更简洁
So far, we've only been using the sigmoid function as an activation function,
到目前为止 我们仅使用了 S 型函数作为激活函数
but there are, of course,
但实际上
a lot of different ones you want to use.
有很多其他激活函数可以使用
Really the only requirement is that,
唯一的要求是
these activation functions should typically be non-linear.
这些激活函数应该是非线性的
So, if you want your network to be able to learn non-linear correlations and patterns,
如果你希望网络能学习非线性关系和规律
and we want the output to be non-linear,
希望输出是非线性的
then you need to use non-linear activation functions in your hidden layers.
那么你需要在隐藏层里使用非线性激活函数
So, a sigmoid is one example.
S 型函数就是一个示例
The hyperbolic tangent is another.
双曲正切是另一种激活函数
One that is pretty much used all the time,
ReLU 是使用最频繁的激活函数
like almost exclusively as activation function and hidden layers,
它一直是隐藏层的激活函数
is the ReLU, so the rectified linear unit.
ReLU 是线性修正单元的简称
This is basically the simplest non-linear function that you can use,
它是最简单的非线性函数
and it turns out that networks tend to train a lot faster
与 S 型函数和双曲正切函数相比
when using ReLU as compared to sigmoid and hyperbolic tangent,
使用 ReLU 时网络的训练速度快多了
so ReLU was what we typically use.
因此我们通常使用 ReLU
Okay. So, here, you're going to build your own neural network, that's larger.
好的下面你的任务是构建更大型的神经网络
So, this time, it's going to have two hidden layers,
这次网络将有两个隐藏层
and you'll be using the ReLU activation function for this on your hidden layers.
你将在隐藏层上使用 ReLU 激活函数
So using this object-oriented class method within a.module,
请在 nn 模块里使用面向对象类方法
go ahead and build a network that looks like this,
构建这样的网络
with 784 input units,
它有 784 个输入单元
a 128 units in the first hidden layer,
第一个隐藏层有 128 个单元
64 units and the second hidden layer,
第二个隐藏层有 64 个单元
and then 10 output units. All right. Cheers.
然后是 10 个输出单元加油！